# SURENDER NATARAJAN

SOFTWARE QATESTER ♥ CHENNAI \$8939117845

o DETAILS o

Chennai 8939117845 surensura46@gmail.com

SKILLS

MySQL

Git

**JavaScript** 

Selenium

**JIRA** 

**Manual Testing** 

Cucumber

Postman

Rest API

Microsoft Azure

LANGUAGES

English

Tamil

#### PROFILE

Highly Motivated Quality Assurance/Control Engineer with 4.5+ years of experience in Both Manual and Automation Testing. Coordinate with product development teams and software engineers to recommend solutions to maximize performance and efficiency. Test case Design, Execution and Defect deduction. Highly Proficient in SIT, UAT, Production Stage.

### EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

#### Senior Software Engineer at Mindtree Ltd., Chennai

March 2020 — November 2021

**Client:** Procter & Gamble -Pampers( Gift to Grow)

#### Roles & Responsibilities:

- Testedhighly responsive user interface components by deploying React concepts and advanced features of Next JS framework.
- Tested and executed Regression test cases of developed software components.
- Good knowledge on creating the build and release pipelines for deploying the application in Microsoft Azure platform.
- Created the API's for managing the incoming request from client side and integrating them with the back end system (Nodejs).
- Ability to translate the designs and Worked in a high-speed, agile environment to deliver features in the shortest time possible.
- Mentor junior members of the team, overseeing QA work efforts and quality.

# Programmer Analyst at Cognizant Technology Solutions, Chennai

June 2018 — March 2020

Client: E\*Trade Financial Corp., Jersey City U.S.A

## Roles & Responsibilities:

#### 1. EQUITY EDGE ONLINE

- · Working in DIT,SIT,UAT and Release
- DIT Designing Test Case, Creating Test Plan, Creating Execution set in JIRA, Uploading Test cases to JIRA Set
- SIT BCT(Backward Compatibility Testing) done in Before DB, After DB, After APP,BAT Test cases Identification for Business Requirements, SIT Execution, Identifying Defects
- UAT BCT(Backward Compatibility Testing) done in Before DB, After DB, After APP
  ,Executing Main Functionality and Prioritizing the User Story for Effective Testing,
  Automating the User stories using Cucumber Feature File and Committing to
  release branch using GIT commands, Cross Browser Testing, Adhoc Testing, Sanity
  Testing, OS Automation Release RAC1, RAC2, Node Testing, Sanity Testing, Normal
  Mode Testing.

#### 2. SERINE:

- Understanding user Requirements and Identifying Automation scope Involved in maintenance of existing Test Scripts required for the updating of regression test suite
- Automation framework design and implementation according to project structure Creating, Enhancing, Debugging and Running Test Cases

- Preparing Reusable functions, which improve the robustness, re-usability, and maintainability of the test scripts Preparing Knowledge Repository for future reference
- Coordination with Functional Testing team and Development team to solve the issues Work along with Business and Client subject matter experts to determine and build the automation suite
- Do's: Performance Testing, Manual Testing, Execute Test Plans, Test Frameworks, Test Plans, Selenium Web driver, Test Automation Tools, Automated Test Scripts.

## Program Analyst trainee at Cognizant Technology Solutions , Chennai

September 2017 — May 2018

Client: Discover Financial Services, Illinois, USA

#### Roles & Responsibilities:

- Monitoring and running AutoSys Jobs and provide reports to End
- LICOTO
- Provide DSR (Daily Status Report) with escalated ticket resolution and liaised with business and technical leads.
- $\cdot$  Involved in Debugging Issues on PROD environment using Autosys.

#### EDUCATION

BE - Computer Science, Anna University, Chennai

June 2012 — April 2016

## **COURSES**

Certificate by Cambridge Business English Council of Europe with level B1, British English Counsel

January 2016 — February 2016

Dovetail Certification for Software Testing, Cognizant

September 2016 — September 2017

Six Sigma Internal Certification, Cognizant

September 2017 — September 2017